# WILLIAM WHITE

Senior Software Engineer

willwhite.dev

contact@willwhite.dev

(281) 658-0534

github.com/will-white

Aurora, Colorado

in/william-white-76068893

## SUMMARY

Polyglot Software Engineer with 10+ years of demonstrated industry experience with a keen eye of UX and a passion for DevOps / infrastructure. Who has developed an array of web, desktop, batch, and business intelligence solutions, of all sizes. Successful in developing simple solutions for complex problems, optimizing business procedures, processes, and productivity.

SKILLS

CSharp (C#), TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, Java, Languages:

LINQ, SQL, SOAP, JSON, XML, HTML, CSS, LESS,

SASS

Frameworks: React, React Query, Redux, Angular 2+, Node.js,

OpenFAAS, Karma, Jest, DevExpress, MUI, Material,

Bootstrap, Tailwind

.NET, .Net Core, EF, WCF, WPF, MSTest, xUnit, NUnit

Technologies: AWS, Aurora, RDS, SQS, DynamoDB, S3, Lambda,

> SNS, CloudFront, GCP App Engine, Address, Geocoding, GIS, Docker, Kubernetes, RabbitMQ, SSMS, MSSQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## 3/2022 - 3/2024 Senior Software Engineer

SkySlope Inc.

- · Developed, reviewed, and maintained, key fullstack business application with over 2000 unit tests, and 30 pull requests per sprint. While still delivering weekly to bi-weekly product releases.
- · Helped monitor, debug, triage, mitigate, and operate, several applications with over 10 thousand daily concurrent users.
- · Participated and facilitated importing of 100s of thousands users from external integrators, via SSO, and private standalone accounts.
- · Enhanced app experience for monetization purposes with sponsored/partnered ADs without impeding user interactions or performance with app
- Lead initiative to reduce cluster cost by moving to file and data streaming, and deferred executions.
- · Collaborated and worked with half a dozen teams to create one of the most adopted prop tech app.

## 8/2020 - 3/2022 Senior Software Engineer

ARMtech Insurance Services Inc.

- · Developed unified single sign on solution using Angular 2+, Node.js, .NET Core, and Duo Security.
- · Refactored dozens of MSSQL PDF Reports to DevExpress and Angular/HTML based ones.
- · Improved coding standards with use of ESLint, Prettier, and CI/CD scripts using GitLab CI/CD.

## 8/2014 - 8/2020 Software Engineer

ARMtech Insurance Services Inc.

- · Spearheaded performance, and refactoring of core business service that lead to a 45x up lift
- · Implemented use of customized Webpack Hot Module Reloading saving countless hours of development and debugging time across all teams.
- · Built a web-based SaaS B2B application utilizing Angular 2+, Node is, WCF, RabbitMQ, Redis, CouchDB, Entity Framework, MSSQL, Docker, and DevExpress Reporting.
- · Developed and optimized customized business software solutions that helped manage risk more effectively and save tens of millions in capital per quarter.

## **PROJECTS**

Fullstack App etsv-a-like

**Ecommerce Site** 

aithub link

Etsy alike Ecommerce website built with React front end with Swipe integrations and a NestJS REST like backend, PostgreSQL DB, utilizing RabbitMQ for asynchronous integration events. Project repository uses Nrwl monorepo with GitHub CI/CD to automatically test and deploy all UI and services to a Heroku and GCP cloud infrastructure.

**HomeLab** 

Ever evolving bare metal environment in my server rack fulfilling various purposes; utilizing various laaS technologies. Fully controlled via GitOps, using Ansible, Proxmox, Kubernetes, Docker, Grafana, Promethus, ELK, and Fluentd.

## Microservice

# **USDA RMA Insurance Premium Calculation Engine**

github link

Custom Calculation/Business engine that processes Insurance premiums derived from RMA's agricultural custom premium calculations. Downloads, parses, and converts PDF text calculations into dynamically generated CSharp code

## EDUCATION

8/2008 - 12/2013 B.S.E. in Computer Science and Engineering

University of Texas at Arlington